♪No matter how far the distance is, don’t be afraid♪
♪无论距离有多远，都 不要害怕♪
♪Love is gentle and caring♪
♪爱是温柔的，充满关怀的♪
♪Those scars will always heal♪
♪那些伤疤总会愈合的♪
♪They will come together like the flowers of time♪
♪他们会像时光之花一样聚集在一起♪
♪Someone will eventually collect them for you♪
♪最终会有人为 你收集它们♪
♪Keep going, you won’t be alone♪
♪继续前进，你不会孤单♪
♪Conversation with time♪
♪与时间对话♪
♪When the light falls softly, think of it as the answer♪
♪当光线柔和地落下时， 就当作答案吧♪
♪May you find someone in the vast sea of ​​people♪
♪愿你在茫茫人海中找到一个人♪
♪Take a cup of tea and be happy♪
♪品一杯清茶，幸福♪
♪Understand that life is full of regrets♪
♪明白人生 充满遗憾♪
♪There is still love♪
♪还是有爱♪
♪Winter and summer♪
♪冬天和夏天♪
【Love is a panacea】 【Episode 6】
【爱情是灵丹妙药】 【第6集】
[Works funded by major art projects in Sichuan Province in 2022]
【 2022年四川省重大艺术项目资助作品】
[Adapted from Meng Yuyan’s novel "Healing"]
【改编自柠檬雨言小说《治愈》 】
Finally, I finally had this.
最后，我终于吃到了这个。
How delicious.
多么美味呀。
Wei An, why don’t you eat?
维安，你怎么不吃？
The surgery was a success.
手术很成功。
The general is already awake.
将军已经醒了。
We are finally safe.
我们终于安全了。
We were released.
我们被释放了。
Let's celebrate!
让我们庆祝一下吧！
let's go.
我们走吧。
Now is not the time to celebrate.
现在还不是庆祝的时候。
We don't have the biopsy results yet.
我们还没有 活检结果。
the general said
将军说
Who is not afraid of death?
谁不怕死，
He knows nothing but is afraid of death.
他什么都不懂，只怕死。
Moreover, Dr. Gu has found the general's enemy.
而且，顾医生已经找到了 将军的敌人。
Let us drink another toast to Dr. Gu.
让我们再次为顾博士干杯。
Thanks.
谢谢。
You have worked hard.
你辛苦了。
wait.
等待。
Why don't any of you drink? I'm the only one drinking.
为什么 你们没人喝酒？只有我在喝酒。
My boss says alcohol paralyzes the central nervous system.
我的老板说酒精会麻痹 中枢神经系统。
And affect the accuracy of surgery.
并影响手术的精准度。
Wei An, why don’t you have a drink too?
维安，你怎么不也喝点酒呢？
You don't need surgery.
你不需要做手术。
She doesn't need surgery, but she should consider it
她不需要做手术， 但她也应该考虑
Potential risk of brain shrinkage caused by alcohol.
酒精导致脑萎缩的潜在风险。
arts.
文。
Eating shrimp can nourish the brain.
吃虾可以补脑。
You end up with brain atrophy.
你最终会患上脑萎缩。
You don't drink because your resistance to alcohol is low.
你不喝酒是因为你 对酒精的抵抗力很低。
After one drink, you will become drunk.
喝一杯之后，你就会醉。
can you see it?
你能看到吗？
Let's drink.
我们喝吧。
Come on, let's have a drink.
来吧，我们喝酒吧。
You don't need to finish your drink.
你不需要喝完酒。
[Evidence Department] I drank all the wine.
【证据部】 我喝完了所有的酒。
Hello.
你好。
I see.
我明白。
Biopsy results are ready.
活检结果已准备好。
Doctor Gu.
顾医生。
our team
我们的队伍
A very important battle was won.
赢得了一场非常重要的战斗。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Average.
一般的。
The surgery was a success.
手术很成功。
But the battle was not won.
但这场战斗并未获胜。
Biopsy results show
活检结果显示
Tumors are more malignant.
肿瘤恶性程度较高。
Although all affected tissue was removed,
尽管所有受影响的组织都被切除了，
The recurrence rate of malignant tumors is very high.
恶性肿瘤的复发率非常高。
How long can I live?
我还能活多久？
It depends on the rate of progress.
这取决于进展速度。
possible
可能
half a year,
半年，
But not more than two years.
但不超过两年。
No one can be invincible forever.
没有人能够永远立于不败之地。
Thank you
谢谢你
Let me know who I'm up against.
让我知道我的对手是谁。
Sue, are you sad?
苏，你难过吗？
Are you still worried about not being able to charge for my wine?
你还担心我的酒收不了钱吗？
You are like Grandet.
你就像格朗台。
I'll make sure you make enough money soon.
我会确保你 很快赚到足够的钱。
Next month, come to my house for a New Year's party.
下个月，来 我家里参加新年聚会。
We would get drunk together.
我们会一起喝醉。
So, look,
所以，看，
We would drink lots and lots of wine.
我们会喝很多很多的酒。
You will make a lot of money.
你会赚很多钱。
Jiang, are you finished?
蒋，你说完了吗？
immediately.
马上。
Come on, don't be late.
快点，别迟到了。
Otherwise the general will be angry.
不然将军会生气的。
OK
好的。
I have found it.
我已经找到了。
What's this?
这是什么？
My lucky charm.
我的幸运符。
Wei'an.
Wei'an.
I'm looking at the stars
我看着星星
And interpret my destiny.
并解读我的命运。
Tonight, Venus is overhead.
今晚，金星在头顶。
The stars align in the house of love.
星星排列 在爱之宫。
Love rating is five stars.
爱情评级为五颗星。
And this night,
而这个晚上，
I'm going to meet my prince.
我要去见我的王子了。
I was so excited thinking about this.
想到这一点我非常激动。
What does this have to do with your amulet?
这和你的护身符有什么关系？
It has a lot to do with this.
与此有很大关系。
It will bring me good luck in love.
它会给我带来爱情的好运。
Jiang.
蒋.
all
全部
in your life
在你的生活中
There is a certain sense of ritual.
有一定的仪式感。
I heard there is a custom in Lakaya.
听说拉卡亚有一个习俗。
When the New Year's bell rings,
当新年的钟声敲响时，
You kiss the people around you,
你亲吻你身边的人，
And you will have good luck all year long.
并且你一整年都会有好运。
Do they have this custom?
他们有这个习俗吗？
You read too many romance novels.
你的言情小说读太多了。
Don't you believe it?
你不相信吗？
In Lakaya, you have to adapt to their customs.
在拉卡亚， 你必须适应他们的习俗。
Even if Dr. Gu is by my side tonight ,
即使今晚 顾医生就在我身边，
I will kiss him.
我会吻他。
do not regret.
不要后悔。
I won't do it.
我不会这么做。
I don't have time to make other people like me.
我没有时间 让别人喜欢我。
Okay, go get your hair done quickly.
好的，赶紧去把 头发弄好。
quickly! go.
快速地！去。
quickly!
快速地！
Wei'an.
Wei'an.
You look beautiful today.
今天你看起来很漂亮。
The date was stuck and he was strangling me.
日期被卡住了，他正在勒死我。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
You look handsome.
你看起来很帅。
So when we get there I have to stay away from you,
所以当我们到达那里时， 我必须远离你，
Otherwise the girls won't see me.
不然女孩们 就看不到我了。
Why haven't they come yet?
他们怎么还没来？
We have been waiting for them for a long time.
我们已经等他们很久了。
Luxurious cars and beautiful women.
豪车和美女。
It's worth the wait.
等待是值得的。
Girls, get in the car.
姑娘们，上车吧。
I want to go to the back seat.
我想去后座。
Fang Mingfan, you drive.
方明凡，你开车。
Translator Jiang, sit in front.
蒋翻译，坐前面。
Why are you looking at me like this?
你为什么这样看着我？
Am I weird to you?
我对你来说很奇怪吗？
you
你
Don't you have a cold?
你没有感冒吗？
He has a handsome face but a clumsy mouth.
他有一张英俊的脸 ，但有一张笨拙的嘴。
they are.
他们是。
You are more beautiful than the moon today.
今天的你比月亮还要美丽。
Am I lucky enough to be your dance partner?
我有幸成为你的舞伴吗？
they are.
他们是。
I chatted with my mentor on the way.
我在路上和我的导师聊天。
Do you want to know what he said?
你想知道他说了什么吗？
Oh, really?
哦真的吗？
When that expressionless guy
当那个面无表情的家伙
Become a turkey with its feathers showing?
变成 一只露出羽毛的火鸡？
Let's talk in the car.
我们在车上聊吧。
You can't let him take Su Translator away.
你不能让 他带走苏翻译。
Wei'an.
Wei'an.
Won't you take me with you?
你不带我一起去吗？
I've never been in a sports car.
我从来没有坐过跑车。
Translated by Jiang.
译者蒋.
You must sit next to me and be my navigator.
你必须坐在 我旁边，成为我的领航员。
Although cell transplantation experiments
虽然 细胞移植实验
Because Huntington's disease has failed,
因为亨廷顿舞蹈症 已经失败了，
Dr. Marta never gave up.
玛塔博士从未放弃。
In fact, this experiment
事实上，这个实验
Has been secretly restarted.
已被秘密重启。
Really?
真的吗？
have you solved it
你已经解决了吗
A key step to improving survival rates?
提高生存率的关键一步？
Does the new experiment involve transplanting your own cells?
新实验涉及 移植你自己的细胞吗
o Culture cells?
o 培养细胞？
Has it entered the clinical stage?
已经进入临床阶段了吗？
Have they started recruiting volunteers?
他们开始招募志愿者了吗？
Take it easy.
放轻松。
Your constant questions make me dizzy.
你不断的问题 让我头晕。
they are.
他们是。
I thought you would be interested in this news.
我以为你会对这个新闻感兴趣。
but i didn't expect
但我没想到
You will know the details so well
你会如此了解细节
An experiment about a rare disease.
关于一种罕见疾病的实验。
they are.
他们是。
Talking about medicine so seriously
如此认真地谈论医学
Make you charming.
让你魅力四射。
I admire you more and more.
我越来越佩服你了。
Do I admire it?
我佩服吗？
No kidding.
别开玩笑。
I'm not kidding.
我不是在开玩笑。
You have a natural charm that you don't know you have.
你有一种 你不知道的天生魅力。
among the crowd,
在人群中间，
you always stand out
你总是脱颖而出
You will attract attention.
你会引起注意。
Look, he's looking at you.
瞧，他正在看着你。
He's looking at you too.
他也在看着你。
So does he.
他也是。
Actually I wouldn't mind
其实我不会介意
Let her have more than one knight beside the princess.
让她在公主身边拥有不止一位骑士。
I'm not a princess,
我不是公主，
I don't need a knight.
我不需要骑士。
Boss, you are drinking to drown your sorrows here .
老板，你在这里借酒浇愁 。
If you continue to drink,
如果你继续喝酒，
Translator Su
译者苏
He's really going to be with that peacock.
他真的会和那只孔雀在一起的。
sorry.
对不起。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
(Gu Yunzheng, what’s wrong with you?)
（顾云正，你怎么了？）
Dear guests, please pay attention.
各位嘉宾请注意。
There are still ten minutes left until the New Year countdown.
距离新年倒计时还有十分钟。
When the bell rings,
当钟声响起时，
let's hug and kiss
让我们拥抱和亲吻
Under fireworks.
烟花下。
I am not wrong.
我没有错。
But why are the celestial phenomena wrong?
但为什么 天象是错误的呢？
It's New Year's Eve
现在是除夕夜
I will meet my prince.
我会见到我的王子。
But the day is almost over
但这一天已经快结束了
And my prince has not come yet.
而我的王子还没有到来。
Jiang.
蒋.
I've been looking for you and here you are.
我一直在寻找你，而你就在这里。
【Daily Love Luck】
【每日爱情运】
because
因为
It's you?
是你？
what happened?
发生了什么？
I think you are disappointed to see me.
我觉得你 见到我很失望。
Gosh, that's not it, is it?
天哪，不是这样的，是吗？
Can I exchange it for another one?
我可以换另一张吗？
please.
请。
Change who? Change what?
改变谁？改变什么？
Change my luck in love.
改变我的爱情运。
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
what you up to?
你想做什么？
It's getting colder.
天越来越冷了。
I'm worried you might catch a cold.
我担心你会感冒。
Don't do that. I do not like you.
不要那样做。我不喜欢你。
What if I want to like you?
如果我想喜欢你怎么办？
Build bridges to this sanctuary.
架起这座避难所的桥梁。
Eres tan molesto, Fang Mingfan.
Eres tan molesto, Fang Mingfan.
what did I do?
我做了什么？
You see, according to the astrology,
你看，根据星象，
Today I am going to meet my prince.
今天我要去见我的王子。
prince?
王子？
are you talking about me?
你是在说我吗？
No, I hope it's not you.
不，我希望不是你。
Mira.
米拉.
A few minutes later,
几分钟后，
The New Year's bell is about to ring.
新年的钟声即将敲响。
No one comes here but me .
除了我之外，没有人会来这里 。
so
所以
Who accepts destiny .
谁接受了命运的 安排。
what you up to?
你想做什么？
they are.
他们是。
If the rope is too tight, it will break.
如果绳子太紧， 就会断掉。
You should allow yourself to enjoy yourself every now and then.
你应该时不时地让自己享受一下。
Otherwise you will be bored
不然你会很无聊
Over the years.
多年来。
not all
不是全部
They still have many years to go.
他们还有很多年的路要走。
Life is short.
生命短暂。
Some people don't want to waste even a minute.
有些人连一分钟都不想浪费。
So we must cherish time
所以我们一定要珍惜时间
And enjoy the moment.
并享受当下。
Lunar New Year's eve
除夕
This is the time to say goodbye and welcome something new.
这是告别 并迎接新事物的时刻。
Death is a farewell and a beginning.
死亡是一次告别 ，也是一个开始。
Thank you all for being here tonight
感谢大家今晚来到这里
at my farewell party
在我的欢送会上
On this special night.
在这个特别的夜晚。
I live a life of fighting.
我过着战斗的生活。
A rocket broke my leg bone.
一枚火箭弹打断了 我的腿骨。
But luckily, I survived.
但幸运的是，我活了下来。
To be alive is a victory.
活着就是一种胜利。
In my final battle,
在我最后的战斗中，
I have encountered my most ferocious enemy.
我遇到了最凶猛的敌人。
Although Dr. Gu Yunzheng of Friendship Hospital
虽然 友谊医院顾云正医生
Help me find this enemy,
帮助我找到了这个敌人，
This time I wasn't so lucky.
这次我就没那么幸运了。
The tumor is malignant
肿瘤是恶性的
It doesn’t take long for it to spread throughout my brain.
很快它就会传遍我的大脑。
I want to shoot him right now
我现在就想开枪打死他
But I can't just leave.
但我不能就这样离开。
I like a Chinese saying very much.
我很喜欢中国的一句话。
When life is at its best,
当生命处于最美好的状态时，
You have to enjoy happiness to the fullest.
你必须充分享受快乐。
I, Kuyat, am not afraid of death.
我，库亚特，并不害怕死亡。
What I fear is that I have never lived.
我害怕的是我从未活过。
Tomorrow I will keep fighting, I will keep hunting,
明天，我将继续战斗，我将继续狩猎，
Like the first day I picked up a gun.
就像我拿起枪的第一天一样。
I will make a grand appearance without any regrets .
我将毫无遗憾地华丽登场 。
I did not come to this life in vain.
我没有白白来到这一生。
This is the farewell party I want
这就是 我想要的告别派对
No tears, just joy.
没有眼泪，只有喜悦。
(I will enter in a gorgeous way and leave no regrets.)
（我会以华丽的方式入场， 不留遗憾。）
(I did not come to this life in vain.)
（我没有白白来到这一生。）
There is a custom in Lakaya.
在拉卡亚有一个习俗。
When the New Year's bell rings,
当 新年的钟声敲响时，
Kissing those around you will bring good luck throughout the year.
亲吻身边的人会带来 这一年的好运。
Let's hug each other tightly and have a passionate kiss!
让我们紧紧拥抱在一起 ，来个热烈的吻吧！
♪Your secret♪
♪你的秘密♪
♪Luckily, I hear all your dreams♪
♪幸运的是， 我听到了你所有的梦想♪
♪Come closer, I can feel the curve of your smile♪
♪靠近一点，我感觉到你笑容的曲线♪
♪This is an extension of happiness♪
♪这是幸福的延伸♪
♪ again and again ♪
♪一次又一次♪
♪My secret♪
♪我的秘密♪
♪I have forgotten that I was once an island♪
♪我已经忘记我曾经是 一座孤岛♪
♪I've been waiting for this moment for a long time♪
♪我等待这一刻 很久了♪
♪I will dream about you again♪
♪我会再次梦见你♪
You said you don't like me, right?
你说过你不喜欢我，对吗？
I... need a favor from you.
我...需要你帮个忙。
Elliot tried to kiss me earlier, didn't you see?
艾略特早些时候试图吻我，你没看到吗？
did you ever forcefully kiss me
你有没有强行吻我
To stop you from kissing Elliot?
阻止你亲吻艾略特？
because?
因为？
you always thought Elliot
你一直以为艾略特
He's handsome, isn't he?
他很帅，不是吗？
Forced kiss?
强吻？
Why do you have so many questions?
你为什么有这么多问题？
You do not want it?
你不愿意吗？
You say you don't want to
你用嘴说你不想
But your body looks genuine.
但你的身体看起来很真诚。
Jiang Muying.
Jiang Muying.
You must share the responsibility with me.
你必须和我一起承担责任。
♪Your secret♪
♪你的秘密♪
♪Luckily, I hear all your dreams♪
♪幸运的是， 我听到了你所有的梦想♪
♪Come closer, I can feel the curve of your smile♪
♪靠近一点，我感觉到你笑容的曲线♪
♪This is an extension of happiness♪
♪这是幸福的延伸♪
♪ again and again ♪
♪一次又一次♪
♪My secret♪
♪我的秘密♪
♪I have forgotten that I was once an island♪
♪我已经忘记我曾经是 一座孤岛♪
♪I've been waiting for this moment for a long time♪
♪我等待这一刻 很久了♪
♪I will dream about you again♪
♪我会再次梦见你♪
(Su Wei'an.)
(Su Wei'an.)
(what's on your mind?)
（你在想什么？）
(Do you have the right to fall in love?)
（你有谈恋爱的权利吗？）
(Why should I kiss him?)
（我为什么要吻他？）
(That idiot really took advantage of me.)
（那个白痴真是利用了我。）
【Gimhae City】 You have a stomach problem.
【金海市】 你胃有问题。
Even if the company encounters financing problems,
即使公司出现 融资问题，
If you are looking for investment,
如果您正在寻找投资，
You shouldn't drink so much.
你不应该喝那么多酒。
Agua.
阿瓜。
Thanks.
谢谢。
If Principal Xu
如果徐校长
It can indeed bring us new funds,
确实能给我们带来新的资金，
Financial pressure for HDQ39 development
HDQ39开发的资金压力
will decrease.
会减少。
I will follow the progress of my father's work.
我将关注 父亲的工作进展。
Don't worry too much.
不要太担心。
but i don't want to
但我不想
I see you working so hard in the future.
看到你以后这么努力。
Of course.
然。
Thank you for always sharing my burden.
谢谢你总是 为我分担负担。
tonight
今晚
I will go to your house.
我会去你家。
You drank a lot,
你喝了很多酒，
So I want to take care of you.
所以我想照顾你。
It's not necessary
没必要吧
Yo...
哟...
I have other things to do.
我还有别的事要做。
Did Su Wei'an really drop out of school ?
苏危安真的退学了吗 ？
certainly.
当然。
[three years ago]
[三年前]
last semester,
上个学期，
Had a big scandal with her best friend
和她最好的朋友闹出了大丑闻
for authorship.
为作者身份。
He even denounced his own teacher.
他甚至谴责自己的老师。
It’s not too much for him to give up his studies in order to become a writer, right?
他为了当作家而放弃学业，也不算过分吧？
I heard
我听说
Wen Ran's father
温然的父亲
Director of the Department of Neurology, Zhanghe Hospital.
张鹤医院神经内科主任。
Su Weian denounced Wen Ran and He Xiaoguang,
苏伟安痛斥 闻染和何晓光，
What's bothering you so much
什么事这么困扰
Go to Zhanghe Hospital and Huaren Hospital.
前往张河医院 、华仁医院。
Good morning sir.
你好先生。
That person is Mr. Du from the Department of Neurology.
那个人是 神经内科的杜学长，
Director Du's son.
杜主任的儿子。
I remember that he and Su Weian had a good relationship.
我记得他和苏伟安 关系还不错。
In the past, I often saw them together in the laboratory
以前，我经常在实验室里看到他们在一起
and frequent trips to the library.
以及经常去图书馆。
[Du Yuncheng] [Wei'an, ¿ abandonaste tus estudios?]
[Du Yuncheng] [Wei'an, ¿abandonaste tus estudios?]
【If you need help, you can come to me at any time. 】
【如果需要帮助， 可以随时来找我。】
[Will Huntington's disease gene carriers develop Huntington's disease? 】
【亨廷顿舞蹈病基因携带者会 患亨廷顿舞蹈病吗？】
Huntington's disease?
亨廷顿氏病？
(Su Weian dropped out of school .)
（苏伟安中途辍学 。）
(Why are you looking for information about Huntington’s disease?)
（您为什么要寻找 有关亨廷顿舞蹈病的信息？）
Yuncheng.
运城。
I asked
我问
All medical universities in Paris.
在巴黎的所有医科大学。
None of them have a student named Su Weian.
他们都没有 一个叫苏伟安的学生。
Her mother said she went to Paris to study.
她妈妈说 她去巴黎读书了。
Keep looking for her.
继续寻找她。
used to be
曾是
Go to some unknown university?
去一些不知名的大学？
impossible.
不可能的。
His grades are very good.
他的成绩非常好。
He did get into a top university.
他确实考上了 一流大学。
Well, I'll keep looking.
嗯，我会继续寻找。
[Vian, where are you? 】
【维安，你在哪里？】
【Resignation report】
【辞职报告】
[library]
[图书馆]
Hello Professor Wen.
温教授您好。
I am Du Yuncheng, the project manager of Jiehui Pharmaceutical.
我是杜云成， 杰辉药业的项目经理。
You go first, I'll be right there.
你先走，我马上过去。
Are you the son of Director Du Yongsong of Huaren Hospital?
你是华仁医院杜永松主任的儿子吧？
do you know me?
你知道我吗？
My daughter talked about you.
我女儿谈到过你。
He said you are his senior.
他说你是他的前辈。
Because you are looking for me?
因为你找我？
Professor Wen.
Profesor Wen.
I speak on behalf of Jiehui Pharmaceutical
我代表杰辉药业发言
About the development of the reactivating drug HDQ39
关于重新激活药物 HDQ39 的开发
For Huntington's disease.
对于亨廷顿舞蹈病。
Are you sure you want to invest?
您确定要投资吗
In the HDQ39 project?
在HDQ39项目中？
What you should know about Huntington’s disease
你应该知道 亨廷顿舞蹈症
Extremely rare in the world.
世界上极为罕见。
[Library] (Global incidence no.)
[图书馆] （全球发病率没有）
(More than 3/10,000. The number of patients in China is less than 3,000.)
（超过3/10,000。中国患者人数 不到3,000。）
(Why invest in research)
（为什么要投资 研究）
(A drug to treat this rare disease?)
（治疗这种罕见疾病的药物？）
(This medicine makes sense to me.)
（这个药 对我来说很有意义。）
(I have important reasons to investigate it.)
（我有重要的理由 去调查它。）
(Wei'an.)
(Wei'an.)
(If HDQ39 is developed successfully)
（如果HDQ39开发成功的话）
(And brings hope for Huntington's disease,)
（并为亨廷顿病带来希望，）
(Can you come back?)
（你能回来吗？）
【Friendship Hospital】
【友谊医院】
Your son has
你儿子有
Subarachnoid hemorrhage.
蛛网膜下腔出血。
That?
那？
what are you saying?
你在说什么？
Subarachnoid hemorrhage.
蛛网膜下腔出血。
Do you have a tumor on your head?
你的头上有肿瘤吗？
No
不
You worry.
你担心。
You say this is not a problem?
你说这不是问题吧？
That? this?
那？这？
here.
这里。
I do not understand.
我不明白。
I see.
我明白。
you do not know.
你不知道。
I know.
我知道。
No, I still don't understand.
不，我还是不明白。
Miss.
女士。
return
回来
here
这里
this afternoon.
今天下午。
The translator will be here by then.
到时候翻译人员就到了。
OK?
好的？
OK
好的。
Fang Mingfan.
Fang Mingfan.
Where are those two translators?
那两个翻译在哪里？
Why hasn’t Su Wei’an come yet?
苏薇安怎么还没来？
You should ask yourself.
你应该问自己。
boss.
老板。
What did you do yesterday?
你昨天做了什么？
Al...
艾尔...
Bring Su Wei'an,
带苏危安来，
Come for consultation.
来咨询。
It's not Su Wei'an's turn to work today.
今天没轮到苏危安上班。
You kissed her forcefully last night.
昨晚你强行吻了她。
Can't she avoid you for a few days?
她就不能躲你几天吗？
Then, bring Jiang Muying here.
那么，就把江暮影带到这里吧。
Or you call her.
或者你给她打电话。
I've already called him. no answer.
我已经给他打过电话了。没有回答。
What happened between you?
你们之间发生了什么事？
She forcefully kissed me last night.
昨晚她强行吻了我。
Can't she avoid you for a few days?
她就不能躲你几天吗？
what's on your mind?
你在想什么？
Boss, I was forcefully kissed.
老大，我被强吻了。
Don't you care about me at all?
你就不关心我一点吗？
I can be a little worried about you.
我可以有点担心你。
Why was it so sudden last night?
昨晚怎么突然
Did you kiss Translator Su?
你吻了苏翻译吗？
Are you interested in her?
你对她感兴趣吗？
Have you checked all the rooms?
你检查过所有的房间吗？
they are.
他们是。
Good morning darling.
早上好亲爱的。
The French are really romantics.
法国人真是浪漫主义者。
Not long ago, he came here to pursue Su Translation.
不久前，他来这里 追求苏翻译。
uncle?
叔叔？
Who did he call uncle?
他叫谁叔叔？
"Couchou" means "honey"
“Couchou”的意思是“蜂蜜”
French.
法语。
You are my dear too.
你也是我的亲爱的。
this is life.
这就是生活。
Whatever you want to know, I will tell you.
你想知道什么，我都会告诉你。
You said there is progress in research.
你说 研究有进展。
Has the drug passed animal testing?
该药通过 动物试验了吗？
Huntington's disease?
亨廷顿病？
These are data from Henri Mondo's laboratory
这些是来自 Henri Mondo 实验室的数据
My mentor sent this to me today.
我的导师今天发给我的。
I'll print a copy for you.
我给你打印一份。
Thanks.
谢谢。
[Cellular and Molecular Neurobiology]
[细胞和分子神经生物学]
We received complaints from doctors at the hospital
我们收到了医院医生的投诉
The man illegally occupied the space,
该男子 非法占用该空间，
Bringing uninspected food
带来未经检查的食物
Seriously affecting work order and environmental sanitation.
严重影响 工作秩序和环境卫生。
Translator Su asked him to leave temporarily.
苏翻译，请他 暂时离开。
complaint?
投诉？
We are outdoors.
我们在户外。
we often drink coffee
我们经常喝咖啡
We eat sandwiches here.
我们在这里吃三明治。
Who files a complaint?
谁提出投诉？
Let’s talk somewhere else.
我们换个地方谈谈吧。
Wei'an.
Wei'an.
I will return to Paris next month.
下个月我将返回巴黎。
Do you want to go to Henri Mondor's laboratory?
您想去 Henri Mondor 实验室吗？
Can you take me to see Dr. Marta?
你能带我去拜访玛塔医生吗？
Not just a visit.
不只是参观。
I'm asking you,
我在问你，
Would you like to work in Henri Mondor's laboratory?
您想 在 Henri Mondor 实验室工作吗？
Oh, really?
哦真的吗？
You will be able to work with Dr. Marta.
您将能够与玛尔塔博士一起工作。
Will you go to Paris with me?
你愿意跟我一起去巴黎吗？
Can I participate in Huntington's disease research?
我可以参加 亨廷顿舞蹈症研究吗？
but I...
但是我...
I only have a bachelor's degree from China Medical University.
我只有中国医科大学的学士学位。
Is this acceptable?
这是可以接受的吗？
I checked it out specifically.
我特意查了一下。
In France, degrees from Huaren Medical University are recognized.
在法国，华仁医科大学的学位是被承认的。
In Dr. Marta's laboratory,
在玛塔博士的实验室里，
There are research assistants with a bachelor's degree.
有 具有学士学位的研究助理。
¡ Amiable!
¡和蔼可亲！
great!
伟大的！
But you have to be prepared.
但你必须做好准备。
Huntington's disease is very rare.
亨廷顿舞蹈病非常罕见。
Research on new drugs will be a long-term endeavor.
新药的研究 将是一项长期的工作。
who knows,
谁知道，
You may have to stay in Paris for many years.
你可能要 在巴黎呆很多年。
no problem.
没问题。
I would do anything if Huntington's disease could be cured .
如果亨廷顿氏舞蹈病能被治愈 ，我愿意做任何事。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
come over.
过来。
You leave during work hours.
你在工作时间离开。
I told you
我告诉你了
What are the consequences of leaving your position, remember?
离开你的职位会有什么后果，还记得吗？
I have to rest today.
今天我必须休息。
It was Jiang's turn to go to work.
轮到蒋上班了。
Besides, Jiang can handle it himself now.
况且江现在自己也能应付自如了。
Yes, she did a great job.
是的，她做得很好。
Intracranial aneurysm removal
颅内动脉瘤平移除外
as an intracranial tumor
作为颅内肿瘤
and cerebral arterial malformations such as cerebral arterial adhesion,
以及脑 动脉粘连等脑动脉畸形，
Other translations are acceptable.
其他翻译是可以接受的。
At least in comparison
至少相比之下
And those who fall in love during working hours,
和那些在工作时间谈恋爱的人，
She is more responsible.
她比较有责任感一点。
Who are you implying?
你在暗示谁？
Who takes up work time to fall in love?
谁占用工作时间去谈恋爱？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
french man
法国男人
They have always been known for their pursuit of romance and novelty.
他们一向以追求浪漫和新颖而闻名。
They can speak sweet words effortlessly.
他们可以毫不费力地说甜言蜜语。
You shouldn't take it seriously.
你不应该认真对待它。
I just want to remember you.
我只是想记住你。
Don't be anxious about love,
爱情不要着急，
Lest your dreams be shattered and your work affected.
以免你的美梦 被打破，从而影响你的工作。
Professor Gu, don't worry.
顾教授，别担心。
As a temporary translator,
作为一名临时翻译，
I won't cause any problems
我不会造成任何问题
to the medical team.
到医疗队。
That was not what I meant.
我不是这个意思。
That's what I mean.
这就是我的意思。
And, in the future, this situation will never happen again.
并且，今后，这样的情况 不会再发生了。
I'm resigning.
我要辞职了。
give up?
放弃？
Espera, Su Wei'an.
Espera, Su Wei'an.
I'm just reminding you.
我只是提醒你一下。
You don't need to get angry and quit.
你不需要生气 然后退出。
I'm not angry.
我没有生气。
This is a carefully considered decision.
这是一个经过深思熟虑的决定。
Was it because of that kiss?
是因为那个吻吗？
Yo...
哟...
There's no need to take it so seriously.
没有必要这么认真地对待它。
that kiss
那个吻
This is just a local New Year custom.
这只是当地的过年习俗。
you are close
你很接近
At that time, so I...
那个时候，所以我...
You...shouldn't take it seriously.
你……不应该认真对待它。
Professor Gu, there is no need to remind me about this.
顾教授， 这个不用提醒我了。
It's just a kiss.
这只是一个吻。
Of course I don't take it seriously.
当然我不认真对待它。
so,
所以，
Why did you resign?
你为什么辞职？
for money.
为了钱。
I found a more lucrative job.
我找到了一份更赚钱的工作。
I'm leaving here and going to Paris.
我要离开这里，去巴黎。
So please,
所以，请，
Don't get in my way of making money.
别妨碍我 赚钱。
♪Olvida is not important♪
♪奥尔维达不重要♪
♪You are the one who gives me courage♪
♪你是给我勇气的人♪
♪Scenery you will never see♪
♪永远也看不到的风景♪
♪I wish you all the best♪
♪祝你一切顺利♪
♪Olvida is not important♪
♪奥尔维达不重要♪
♪I am the one who saved me♪
♪拯救我的人是我♪
♪Siempre te amaré♪
♪Siempre te amaré♪
♪Nunca me rindo♪
♪Nunca me rindo♪
Are you going to France?
你要去法国吗？
So suddenly?
这么突然？
Suddenly I received a big order.
突然接到一个大订单。
I have to go there.
我必须去那里。
I'm going to Paris.
我要去巴黎。
All right.
好吧。
Wherever you go, take me with you.
无论你去哪里，都带上我。
OK?
好的？
Jiang.
蒋.
If you follow me, you'll just be at a loss
如果你跟着我，你只会不知所措
And you don't need money.
而且你不需要钱。
listen to me. Go home quickly.
听我说。快点回家吧。
No.
不。
I came all the way here just to find you.
我千里迢迢跑来就是为了找你。
You can't leave me alone anymore.
你不能再丢下我一个人了。
never.
决不。
Plus, I've never been to Paris.
另外，我从来没有去过巴黎。
Take me with you.
带我一起走。
Are you really going to leave me alone and go away?
你真的打算丢下我一个人 然后自己走吗？
listen. impossible.
听。不可能的。
Three years ago, I didn't see it coming.
三年前，我没有预见到它的到来。
But this time,
但这一次，
I won't let you go alone.
我不会让你一个人走。
Otherwise, please let me know.
否则，请告诉我。
Because you're leaving? where are you going? How long will you stay there?
因为你要离开？你要去哪里？ 你要在那里呆多久？
and,
并且，
Why did you suddenly give up your studies?
你为什么 突然放弃学业？
Why did you give up your dream of becoming a doctor?
你为什么放弃 当医生的梦想？
You have to explain all this to me clearly.
这一切你都要跟我说清楚。
Yo...
哟...
I'm going to run away with Elliot
我要和艾略特一起逃跑
Escape?
逃脱？
precise.
精确的。
So, Jiang, you can't follow me.
所以，姜，你不能跟着我。
Are you going to elope with Elliot?
你要和艾略特私奔吗？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
I know you like Gu Yunzheng.
我知道你喜欢顾云铮。
You can hide it from others,
你可以向别人隐藏它，
But not me.
但不是我。
You 've liked him since you were in college, right?
你 大学的时候就喜欢他了，对吧？
And, you two kissed at that New Year's party.
而且，你们两个 在那次新年聚会上接吻了。
now you tell me
现在你告诉我
you want to run away
你要逃跑
With a French man you barely know?
和一个 你几乎不认识的法国男人？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
I'm actually not stupid.
我其实并不傻。
Jiang.
蒋.
El besoque le di a Gu Yunzheng
El beso que le di a Gu Yunzheng
It's just a New Year gesture
这只是新年的一个姿态
Doesn't have any special meaning.
没有任何特殊意义。
It was love at first sight with Eliot.
与艾略特一见钟情。
He is the love of my life.
他是我一生的挚爱。
I'm going to France with him.
我要和他一起去法国。
and know,
并且知道，
Love has no logic
爱情没有逻辑
It also doesn't obey orders.
它也不服从命令。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
arts.
文。
Explain this.
解释一下这一点。
Why do you study euthanasia?
你为什么研究安乐死？
Someone asked me for help before;
之前有人向我寻求帮助，
Promises very high commissions.
承诺非常高的佣金。
The commission is very high.
佣金非常高。
So I saved the files but didn't throw them away.
所以我保存了 这些文件，但没有扔掉它们。
Do you think I want to die?
你觉得我想死吗？
I'm still alive and well.
我现在还活得这么好。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Did you tell the truth?
你有说实话吗？
Do you really consider me your friend?
你真的把我当你的朋友吗？
you are my best friend.
你是我最好的朋友。
Wei'an.
Wei'an.
no matter what happens,
无论发生什么，
If you have something painful tormenting you,
如果你有什么痛苦的事情折磨着你，
you can tell me.
你可以告诉我。
I know there are some things you can't tell your mother.
我知道有些事情 你不能告诉你妈妈。
But you can tell me.
但你可以告诉我。
I will definitely keep it a secret.
我绝对会保守秘密。
Oh, really.
哦真的吗。
Mira.
米拉.
I have been coming to Lakaya for a long time.
我来拉卡亚已经很长时间了。
I haven't revealed anything about you to Mi-ran.
我没有向美兰透露过你的任何事情。
I'm very reliable.
我很可靠。
And we are like family,
而我们就像家人一样，
best friend.
最好的朋友。
I can help you share a lot.
我可以帮助你分享很多东西。
Pero, Jiang, yo...
Pero, Jiang, yo...
I did not lie to you.
我没有骗你。
I'm really going to run away with Elliot
我真的要和艾略特私奔了
real.
真的。
And you
你呢
You want me to find love too, right?
你也想让我 找到爱情，对吗？
That amulet in my bag
我包里的那个护身符
You put it in, right?
你把它放进去了，对吗？
Trust me, Chiang.
相信我，蒋。
You are so stubborn.
你真是太固执了。
You went to France without telling me the truth, did you?
你要去法国却没有 告诉我真相，是吗？
Bueno.
布埃诺。
If you leave, our friendship is over.
如果你离开，我们的友谊就结束了。
I don't need a friend like you.
我不需要像你这样的朋友。
Jiang.
蒋.
I'm resigning.
我要辞职了。
give up?
放弃？
Was it because of that kiss?
是因为那个吻吗？
There's no need to take it so seriously.
没有必要这么认真地对待它。
that kiss
那个吻
This is just a local New Year custom.
这只是当地的过年习俗。
You were nearby at the time, so I...
当时你就在附近， 所以我...
You...shouldn't take it seriously.
你……不应该认真对待它。
Professor Gu, there is no need to remind me about this.
顾教授， 这个不用提醒我了。
It's just a kiss.
这只是一个吻。
French kiss
法式接吻
This is as normal as eating or drinking.
这就像吃饭或喝水一样正常。
Of course I don't take it seriously.
当然我不认真对待它。
(Gu Yunzheng.)
(Gu Yunzheng.)
(You are a wonderful person in every way.)
（你 在各方面都是一个很棒的人。）
(Why do you only have that stupid mouth?)
（你为什么只有那张笨嘴？）
【Friendship Hospital】
【友谊医院】
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Have you had breakfast?
你已经吃过早餐了吗？
No, it's too forced.
不行，太勉强了。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
This is the glutinous rice balls from the canteen.
这是食堂的汤圆，
Very sweet and sticky.
非常甜又粘。
I bought it for you.
我给你买的。
Al,
艾尔，
I did not mean that.
我不是那个意思。
actually, I...
其实我...
No,
不，
I said too much.
我说太多了。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Let's have breakfast together.
我们一起吃早餐吧。
you can trust
您可以完全信任
On Dr. Gu’s medical skills.
论顾医生的医术。
At Huaren Hospital in China,
在中国华仁医院，
He is the youngest associate doctor.
他是最年轻的副博士。
Although he looks a little reserved
虽然看起来有些矜持
and distant,
和遥远的，
Very responsible
非常负责
with every patient.
与每一位患者。
So, don't worry.
所以，不用担心。
This operation will definitely be successful.
这次手术肯定会成功。
Genial, Su Wei'an.
Genial, Su Wei'an.
You are so aggressive in front of me.
你在我面前如此咄咄逼人。
But behind my back, you praised me.
但在我背后， 你却对我大加赞赏。
You are hypocritical.
你很虚伪。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Doctor Gu.
顾医生。
I was just going to find you.
我正想去找你呢。
This is for you.
这是给您的。
[Resignation letter] This is my resignation letter.
[辞职信] 这是我的辞职信。
Although this is a temporary job,
虽然这是一份临时工作，
I think it should be formal.
我觉得应该是正式的。
I appreciate your time helping me.
我很感激你帮助我的时间。
I hope you find it soon
我希望你能尽快找到它
Leave it to a more qualified translator.
交给更有资格的翻译。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
you have a good command of french
你有很好的法语水平
and medical history.
和病史。
Find the right translator
寻找合适的翻译员
soon
很快
not simple.
不简单。
and
和
You want to make money,
你想赚钱，
There is no need to go to France.
没有必要去法国。
I can give you a raise.
我可以给你加薪。
It's not necessary
没必要吧
It's not just about money.
这不仅仅是钱的问题。
so give it to me
所以给我
a reason that satisfies me
一个令我满意的理由
Reasons why you should give up on something again
你要再次放弃某事的原因
Half.
半。
You said it's not about money.
你说这不是钱的问题。
Are you doing this for Elliot?
你这样做是为了艾略特吗？
Do you really like Eliot?
你真的喜欢艾略特吗？
Is it for him?
是为了他吗？
If there's nothing more to say, I'll leave first.
如果没什么可说的， 我就先走了。
I need to go to the embassy to apply for an emergency visa.
我需要去大使馆 办理紧急签证。
According to our contract,
根据我们的合同，
Resignation must be submitted one week in advance.
辞职必须 提前一周提出申请。
The resignation will be effective one week after submission.
辞职报告将于提交后一周生效。
During this time,
在这段时间，
You have to keep working.
你必须继续工作。
if you are missing,
如果你失踪了，
They will deduct your wages.
他们会扣除你的工资。
♪Move the hands of the clock at night♪
♪夜晚移动时钟的指针♪
♪The noise gradually replaced the silence♪
♪喧闹渐渐 取代了寂静♪
♪Our representative meeting script♪
♪我们代表会议脚本♪
♪Embedded night rainbow♪
♪嵌入夜间彩虹♪
♪And the wind that passes through the desert♪
♪还有穿过沙漠的风♪
♪Everyone is a witness to our past♪
♪大家都是我们过去的见证者♪
♪No one can escape being lost in the vast world♪
♪没有人能逃脱 在广阔的世界中迷失♪
♪Looking for the one in a million possibility♪
♪寻找 百万分之一的可能性♪
♪Trapped in this city called destiny♪
♪被困在这座名为命运的城市♪
♪But still chasing stars♪
♪但还是追星♪
♪Don't worry, I love those who are lost♪
♪别担心，我爱 那些迷失的人♪
♪Holding a cup to warm the lonely soul♪
♪捧杯， 温暖孤独的灵魂♪
♪Let me hug your crack♪
♪让我拥抱你的裂缝♪
♪You shine like a shining star♪
♪你就像 一颗闪亮的星星一样闪耀♪
♪Blink in lonely moments♪
♪在孤独的时刻眨眼♪
♪Move the hands of the clock at night♪
♪夜晚移动时钟的指针♪
♪The noise gradually replaced the silence♪
♪喧闹渐渐 取代了寂静♪
♪Our representative meeting script♪
♪我们代表会议脚本♪
♪Embedded night rainbow♪
♪嵌入夜间彩虹♪
♪And the wind that passes through the desert♪
♪还有穿过沙漠的风♪
♪Everyone is a witness to our past♪
♪大家都是我们过去的见证者♪
♪No one can escape being lost in the vast world♪
♪没有人能逃脱 在广阔的世界中迷失♪
♪Looking for the one in a million possibility♪
♪寻找 百万分之一的可能性♪
♪Trapped in this city called destiny♪
♪被困在这座名为命运的城市♪
♪But still chasing stars♪
♪但还是追星♪
♪Don't worry, I love those who are lost♪
♪别担心，我爱 那些迷失的人♪
♪Holding a cup to warm the lonely soul♪
♪捧杯， 温暖孤独的灵魂♪
♪Let me hug your crack♪
♪让我拥抱你的裂缝♪
♪You shine like a shining star♪
♪你就像 一颗闪亮的星星一样闪耀♪
♪Blink in lonely moments♪
♪在孤独的时刻眨眼♪